{
"JavaQuiz": [
  {
    "question": "How do you make a print statement?",
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "choices": [
      "System.out.print",
      "System.out",
      "print"
    ],
    "answer": "System.out.print",
    "feedback": "The correct answer is System.out.print. The other options are not valid in Java to display content."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an object?",
    "type": "drop-down",
    "choices": [
      "Instance of a variable",
      "Instance of a class",
      "Instance of an array"
    ],
    "answer": "Instance of a class",
    "feedback": "The correct answer is instance of a class."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the variable used to declare a number/decimal?",
    "type": "checkbox",
    "choices": [
      "int",
      "decimal",
      "double"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "int",
      "double"
    ],
    "feedback": "Decimal is not used to define a decimal value, instead double is used."
  },
  {
    "question": "To define a variable that never changes, use final before it.",
    "type": "true-false",
    "choices": [
      "true",
      "false"
    ],
    "answer": "true",
    "feedback": "Final is the keyword used to define a variable whoms value will not change."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the value of sum: int sum = 4 + 6; ",
    "type": "fill",
    "answer": "10",
    "feedback": "The correct answer for sum is 10, since 4+6 = 10"
  },
  {
    "question": "How would you declare a variable holding the value: Hello World",
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "choices": [
      "let",
      "var",
      "String"
    ],
    "answer": "String",
    "feedback": "The correct answer is String."
  },
  {
    "question": "On what platform would you run your code to test it?",
    "type": "drop-down",
    "choices": [
      "Google",
      "Word Doc",
      "IDE"
    ],
    "answer": "IDE",
    "feedback": "The correct answer is IDE where you can test your code on your local machine before deployment."
  },
  {
    "question": "What would you declare a method as to avoid overriding?",
    "type": "checkbox",
    "choices": [
      "const",
      "final",
      "permanent"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "final"
      },
    "feedback": "Final is used to prevent variables and functions from being overriden in Java."
  ],
  {
    "question": "JDB is known as Java Debugger.",
    "type": "true-false",
    "choices": [
      "true",
      "false"
    ],
    "answer": "true",
    "feedback": "It is true- JDB known as Java Debugger allows you to debug into your Java class."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the keyword used in function declaration to not return a value?",
    "type": "fill",
    "answer": "void",
    "feedback": "The correct answer is void which are used commonly to set data."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which for loop is not accurate?",
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "choices": [
      "for ( int i = 99; i >= 0; i / 9 )",
      "for ( int i = 0; i >= 50; i++ )",
      "for ( int i = 6; i >= 0; i-- )"
    ],
    "answer": "for ( int i = 99; i >= 0; i / 9 )",
    "feedback": "The iterator of the for loop is not valid in for ( int i = 99; i >= 0; i / 9 )."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which package contains the random class?",
    "type": "drop-down",
    "choices": [
      "java.util package",
      "java.Math package",
      "java.RandomGenerator package"
    ],
    "answer": "java.util package",
    "feedback": "The java.util package must be imported to gain access to the Random class."
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the valid variable types below:",
    "type": "checkbox",
    "choices": [
      "int",
      "String",
      "num"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "int",
      "String"
    ],
    "feedback": "Int and String are valid, num is not a valid variable type."
  },
  {
    "question": "Java allows multiple thread programming.",
    "type": "true-false",
    "choices": [
      "true",
      "false"
    ],
    "answer": "true",
    "feedback": "Java allows multiple threads to be executed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the value of sum: int sum = 4 + 6; ",
    "type": "fill",
    "answer": "10",
    "feedback": "The correct answer for sum is 10, since 4+6 = 10"
  },
  {
    "question": "What it the default amount of elements in an arraylist?",
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "choices": [
      "null",
      "0",
      "10"
    ],
    "answer": "10",
    "feedback": "ArrayList list = new ArrayList() will create an arraylist of 10 elements by default."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the syntax for defining a class?",
    "type": "drop-down",
    "choices": [
      "Class ___ {}",
      "class ___ {}",
      "c ___ {}"
    ],
    "answer": "class ___ {}",
    "feedback": "The correct answer is class ___ {} not with a capital C in class as it is case sensitive."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is valid to check if int i equals 2?",
    "type": "checkbox",
    "choices": [
      "if(i == 2)",
      "if(i = 2)",
      "if(i === 2)"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "if(i == 2)"
    ],
    "feedback": "Since we are checking for equivalency, two double signs are required to check so the answer is: if(i == 2)"
  },
  {
    "question": "You must invoke your functions in your main method.",
    "type": "true-false",
    "choices": [
      "true",
      "false"
    ],
    "answer": "true",
    "feedback": "In Java, you must call your functions in the main method to execute."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fill in the blank: System.out.print__ allows you to print a statement on a new line.?",
    "type": "fill",
    "answer": "ln",
    "feedback": "The correct answer is ln as System.out.println prints out your statement on a new line."
  }
 ]
}
